<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?><!DOCTYPE metadata SYSTEM "http://www.fgdc.gov/metadata/fgdc-std-001-1998.dtd"><metadata>
<idinfo>
<citation>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Avineon, Inc.</origin>
<pubdate>03/30/2004</pubdate>
<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
<title>2001 SRWMD Seagrass- Northern Big Bend</title>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
<pubinfo>
<pubplace>Live Oak, Florida</pubplace>
<publish>Suwannee River Water Management District</publish>
</pubinfo>
<onlink>\\Oakland\e-drive\env\srw_sav\final_inspection\covers\srw_sav01</onlink>
</citeinfo>
</citation>
<descript>
<abstract>The dataset serves as documentation of the seagrass habitat within the Northern Big Bend coastal area from Horseshoe Beach south to Waccasassa Bay, as it existed November 2001.  Seagrass data was photointerpreted from 2001 1:24,000 scale natural color aerial photography and classified using the SFWMD modified FLUCCS classification system. Features were stereoscopically interpreted from the aerotriangulated aerial photography and vector data was compiled using analytical stereoplotters.  

The minimum mapping unit for classification was 0.25 acres (=0.1 hectares). The horizontal accuracy of the data meets NMAS for 1:24,000 scale maps (=/- 40 feet).  Pre-interpretation groundthruthing was performed on the aerial photography.</abstract>
<purpose>This map serves as important management tool for obtaining a current inventory of this resource, identifying "healthy" areas that may deserve special protection efforts, and identifying potential "problem" areas that require further investigation.  The map can also document large-scale trends in the status of this resource and act as a baseline for any future trend analysis of the SAV  resources in the Big Bend coastal region.</purpose>
</descript>
<timeperd>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>11/21/2001</caldate>
<time>11:00 AM</time>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<current>ground condition</current>
</timeperd>
<status>
<progress>Complete</progress>
<update>Unknown</update>
</status>
<spdom>
<bounding>
<westbc>
-83.380587</westbc>
<eastbc>
-82.742638</eastbc>
<northbc>
29.502400</northbc>
<southbc>
28.995502</southbc>
</bounding>
</spdom>
<keywords>
<theme>
<themekey>Seagrass</themekey>
<themekey>SAV</themekey>
<themekey>Benthic</themekey>
<themekey>Halodule wrightii</themekey>
<themekey>Syringodium filiforme</themekey>
<themekey>Thalassia testudinum</themekey>
<themekey>habitat</themekey>
<themekey>submerged vegetation</themekey>
<themekey>FLUCCS</themekey>
<themekey>coastal</themekey>
<themekey>map</themekey>
</theme>
<place>
<placekey>Suwannee River</placekey>
<placekey>Cedar Key</placekey>
<placekey>Horseshoe Beach</placekey>
<placekey>Waccasassa Bay</placekey>
<placekey>Big Bend</placekey>
<placekey>North Florida</placekey>
</place>
</keywords>
<accconst>None</accconst>
<useconst>The positional accuracy of this data meets USGS NMAS for 1:24000 scale maps. This data has a minimum classification accuracy of 90% for all categories.</useconst>
<ptcontac>
<cntinfo>
<cntperp>
<cntper>Keith Patterson</cntper>
<cntorg>Avineon Inc.</cntorg>
</cntperp>
<cntpos>Director of Photogrammetry, Mapping and GIS</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>15500 Lightwave Drive, Suite 200</address>
<city>Clearwater</city>
<state>Florida</state>
<postal>33760</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>727 539-1661</cntvoice>
<cntfax>727 539-6954</cntfax>
<cntemail>kpatterson@avineon.com</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</ptcontac>
<datacred>Acknowledgement of Avineon, Inc. would be appreciated in products derived from this data.</datacred>
<native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.1.2.671</native>
<crossref>
<citeinfo>
<origin>Avineon, Inc., Clearwater, Florida</origin>
<pubdate>March 30, 2004</pubdate>
<pubtime>Unknown</pubtime>
<title>SRW_SAV01</title>
<edition>1st</edition>
<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
</citeinfo>
</crossref>
</idinfo>
<dataqual>
<attracc>
<attraccr>Attribute accuracy was tested by visual comparison of the aerial photographs with the seagrass data to ensure consistency with the classificaton system and photo signatures. Groundtruthing was also performed to aid in delineation and classification of photo signatures. Additional checks for valid attributes were performed. 

Accuracy Assessment of the draft data was conducted in order to ensure that completed photointerpretation was accurate. Avineon did not perform accuracy assessment point sampling on the data. That task was completed by the SRWMD. Avineon did provide the SRWMD with the randomly selected sample points and plots of the draft seagrass data for in-field verification. 

This data has a minimum classification accuracy of 90% for all classes.</attraccr>
</attracc>
<logic>Comparison of the completed seagrass coverage with other data of similar accuracy was performed. The 2001 Seagrass coverage was compared to the 1999 USGS DOQs and the 2001 Oysters coverage. This was done during photointerpretation and quality assurance. 

Polygon topology present. All polygons were tested for closure and no dangles, slivers, or pseudo nodes exist. Every polygon has a label, there are no multiple labels within polygons, there are no contiguous polygons with the same label.</logic>
<complete>Minimum mapping unit for seagrass polygons is 0.25 acres. The study area boundaries for the project were defined by the SRWMD. Seagrass habitat features were captured and classified according to the rules, conventions, and descriptions in the Statement of Work and the Photointerpretation Key for the 2001 SRWMD Seagrass Mapping project.</complete>
<posacc>
<horizpa>
<horizpar>The positional accuracy of this data meets USGS NMAS for 1:24000 scale maps. Horizontal accuracy of the data corresponds to the positional accuracy of the aerotriangulated photography that was controlled by USGS DOQs. Digital linework was reviewed over the 1999 DOQs and positional accuracy checked by navigating to features using coordinates selected from aerotriangulated photography for comparison to linework data collected representing those features.</horizpar>
</horizpa>
</posacc>
<lineage>
<srcinfo>
<srccite>
<citeinfo>
<origin>US Imaging Inc.</origin>
<pubdate>November 21, 2001</pubdate>
<title>2001 Northern Big Bend Aerial Photography</title>
</citeinfo>
</srccite>
<srcscale>1:24000</srcscale>
<typesrc>aerial photography, stereo coverage</typesrc>
<srctime>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>11/21/01</caldate>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
</srctime>
<srccitea>none</srccitea>
<srccontr>photographic signature for interpretation of seagrass data.</srccontr>
</srcinfo>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Field Work 

Avineon, Inc. conducted fieldwork throughout the project in order to assist with accurate photointerpretation. Pre-photointerpretation fieldwork, directed at advance signature identification, was conducted in addition to other fieldwork needed to resolve site-specific questions. The fieldwork was completed in order to identify and classify the signatures appearing on the 2001 aerial photographs. Prior to visiting the field, check sites were selected representing the covertypes and seagrass signatures existing within the project area. 

Groundtruthing of completed photointerpretation work involved collecting the latitude/longitude coordinates for each selected field check as calculated from the aerotriangulated 2001 aerial photographs. These coordinates were then visited on the water using GPS. This part of the fieldwork was used for both the verification of accuracy of completed PI and as a training tool for subsequent photointerpretation work. Selected sites were identified for groundtruthing in the field based on their location and complexity. Typically the sites were complex in nature, particularly in terms of density determination and/or algae presence. 

Data collected for each field check site was entered on Field Data Sheets. The Field Data Sheets were delivered to the District as part of this project.</procdesc>
<procdate>March 3-7, 2003, September 16-18, 2003</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Photointerpretation Key 

Prior to the commencement of mapping, Avineon developed a photointerpretation key for the project. The key contains examples of all FLUCCS classification types delineated for the study and includes both textural descriptions of the classification types along with several aerial photo clips clearly delineated to show users the seagrass signatures on the photos.</procdesc>
<proctime>August 2003</proctime>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Photointerpretation 

Photointerpretation for the project was accomplished on Avineon's Zeiss P3 analytical stereoplotters. 

Seagrass covertype boundaries were photogrammetrically digitized using CadMap/dgn software running on Windows 2000 workstations. This software directly captures digital data into MicroStation NT (Bentley Microsystems, Inc.) for later importation to ARC/INFO. 

Photointerpreters utilized previously collected field data and in-process collection of field data along with other available collateral data to assist in their interpretation. Throughout the photointerpretation process, positional accuracy of seagrass boundaries was maintained according to the photographic signatures apparent on the photography. The following coding and classification system was applied during photointerpretation: 

CODE CLASS NAME- 5400 Bays and Estuaries (Open Water), 5700 Marine (Gulf of Mexico), 6510 Tidal Flats, 9113 Seagrass - Patchy, 9116 Seagrass - Continuous, 0 Land.

5400 Bays and Estuaries.  Open water (non-vegetated) within the study area

5700 Marine (Gulf of Mexico). Open waters of the Gulf of Mexico

6510 Tidal Flats.  Non-vegetated areas of sand and/or mud exposed at least once a year and capable of supporting seagrass populations (i.e., no more than 6 feet in depth)

9113 Seagrass, Patchy.  Isolated patches of seagrasses or extensive areas of patchy seagrass coverage. Usually, these areas include small round clumps of vegetation or elongated strands of seagrass coverage.

9116 Seagrass, Continuous.  Seagrass containing areas that exhibit uniform signatures with less than 25 percent of any particular area showing up as unvegetated bottom features.

0 Not Classified (Land)</procdesc>
<proctime>May - November 2003</proctime>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Quality Assurance and Quality Control 
Avineon has established, documented, implemented and maintains a quality management system and continually improves its effectiveness in accordance with the requirements of ISO 9001:2000, Quality Management System Requirements. 

Avineon's Quality System encompasses customer order entry, design and development, purchasing and receipt of parts and materials, identification and traceability, stocking and issuance of parts and materials, test, inspection, storage, packaging, shipping, delivery and service. Avineon, Inc.'s Quality System meets or exceeds the requirements of ISO 9001:2000, Quality Management Systems - Requirements. 

Our Quality System is designed to ensure products/materials provided by Avineon are subject to adequate control of quality to ensure customer satisfaction. This system is designed to prevent discrepancies from occurring and is enforced with positive corrective action when necessary. 

Quality control reviews were ongoing throughout the project. The datasets were examined for adherence to mapping conventions, the PI Key, spatial and classification accuracy, and photointerpretation consistency. Below is a description of the quality control steps that were used for the 2001 SRWMD Seagrass Mapping Project. 

Aerial Photography Quality Assurance- Upon receipt of the November 2001 aerial photography, Avineon inspected them for tonal balance and contrast, complete areal coverage, and defects prior to acceptance. 

Control Point, Aerotriangulation and Positional Accuracy- Avineon used control points from USGS DOQ's. A Fully Analytical Aerial Triangulation (FAAT) method to extend the ground control was completed. No analog, semi-analytical or high to low triangulation procedures were used. Residuals from the FAAT were continually checked and approved by a photogrammetrist prior to stereocompilation. Avineon used a Zeiss Planicomp analytical stereo instrument for point mensuration. These instruments are calibrated by Zeiss, as a quality assurance practice, on a regular basis. Our analytical stereoplotters were last calibrated in April 2003. Bundle adjustment was performed using PATB software with blunder detection and self-calibration. The positional accuracy of the photointerpreted data was checked by comparing it with positions extracted from the USGS DOQs. The DOQs meet the same positional accuracy required for the project and represent an excellent source for comparison. The positional accuracy of the data was also checked during fieldwork tasks. Prior to seagrass fieldwork, X and Y coordinates were collected from the aerotriangulated photographs as checksites to be visited in the field. These coordinates were stored as waypoints within a GPS unit. Upon visiting the field, the latitude/longitude waypoints were used to navigate precisely to the points derived from the photographs. 

In-Process Photointerpretation Quality Assurance- Avineon's Project Manager and the designated QA Photointerpreter systematically reviewed seagrass delineations and classifications interpreted from the aerial photographs. During quality control review using the analytical stereoplotter, the QA Photointerpreter reviewed the seagrass delineations interpreted on the aerial photographs (these data existed as a .dgn file at this stage of production). A Zeiss analytical stereoplotter with dual optics, that allows two photointerpreters to view the photos simultaneously, was used to point out suggested corrections to the original photointerpreter for correction or revision. The original photointerpreter completed the required revisions and resubmitted the data to the QA Photointerpreter. The work was checked again by the quality assurance photointerpreter prior to delivery as a draft product to the District. Logical Consistency Checks Comparison of the completed seagrass coverage with other data of similar accuracy was performed. The 2001 Seagrass coverage was compared to the 2001 Oysters coverage and the 1999 DOQs. This was done during photointerpretation and quality assurance. 

GIS Coverage Quality Control- The quality of the ArcGIS digital data was monitored by a combination of manual and automated analyses. A set of automated quality control programs were used to check for errors, such as missing polygon label points, label points with no attributes, invalid attribute codes, missing attributes within the info tables, and two adjacent polygons with the same attributes. 

Accuracy Assessment- Accuracy Assessment of the draft data was conducted in order to ensure that completed photointerpretation was accurate. Avineon did not perform accuracy assessment point sampling on the data. That task was completed by the SRWMD. Avineon did provide the SRWMD with the randomly selected sample points and plots of the draft seagrass data for in-field verification.</procdesc>
<procdate>May 2003- March 2003</procdate>
</procstep>
<procstep>
<procdesc>Final Arc Info Coverage 

At the conclusion of the photointerpretation task the Cadmap/dgn data file produced on the analytical stereoplotter was translated to ARC/INFO. Once the data were exported to ARC/INFO, processes for building topology and validating the coverage were completed. 

Unique identifiers (record numbers) for resulting polygons were assigned automatically by the system according to normal ARC/INFO conventions. Before generating label points for each polygon, the graphics were further validated to ensure that no dangling arcs escaped the polygon-building step. Dangling arcs were detected and corrected during an interactive ArcEdit session by technicians trained in vector polygon cleanup. 

A 2001 ARC/INFO seagrass polygon coverage of the entire 2001 SRWMD Seagrass Project area from Horseshoe Beach to Waccasassa Bay was delivered on compact disk.</procdesc>
</procstep>
</lineage>
</dataqual>
<spdoinfo>
<direct>Vector</direct>
<ptvctinf>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>2787</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Label point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>1876</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>1876</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>4</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
<sdtsterm>
<sdtstype>Label point</sdtstype>
<ptvctcnt>1875</ptvctcnt>
</sdtsterm>
</ptvctinf>
</spdoinfo>
<spref>
<horizsys>
<planar>
<gridsys>
<gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn>
<spcs>
<spcszone>903</spcszone>
<lambertc>
<stdparll>29.583333</stdparll>
<stdparll>30.750000</stdparll>
<longcm>-84.500000</longcm>
<latprjo>29.000000</latprjo>
<feast>1968500.000000</feast>
<fnorth>0.000000</fnorth>
</lambertc>
</spcs>
</gridsys>
<planci>
<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
<coordrep>
<absres>0.001171</absres>
<ordres>0.001171</ordres>
</coordrep>
<plandu>survey feet</plandu>
</planci>
</planar>
<geodetic>
<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
<denflat>298.257222</denflat>
</geodetic>
</horizsys>
</spref>
<eainfo>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>
srw_sav01.aat</enttypl>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FNODE#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal node number for the beginning of an arc (from-node).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>TNODE#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal node number for the end of an arc (to-node).</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LPOLY#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal node number for the left polygon.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>RPOLY#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal node number for the right polygon.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>LENGTH</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SRW_SAV01#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SRW_SAV01-ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>User-defined feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
</attr>
</detailed>
<detailed>
<enttyp>
<enttypl>
srw_sav01.pat</enttypl>
</enttyp>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Perimeter of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SRW_SAV01#</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
<attrdomv>
<udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
</attrdomv>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>SRW_SAV01-ID</attrlabl>
<attrdef>User-defined feature number.</attrdef>
<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FLUCSDESC</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Description of FLUCCS Code</attrdef>
<attrdefs>FDOT Florida Land Use/Cover Classification</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>FLUCSCODE</attrlabl>
<attrdef>FLUCCS Code</attrdef>
<attrdefs>FDOT Florida Land Use / Cover Classification System</attrdefs>
</attr>
<attr>
<attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl>
<attrdef>Number of Acres per polygon</attrdef>
</attr>
</detailed>
</eainfo>
<distinfo>
<distrib>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>Suwannee River Water Management District</cntorg>
</cntorgp>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>9225 County Road 49</address>
<city>Live Oak</city>
<state>Florida</state>
<postal>32060</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>386.362.1001</cntvoice>
<cntfax>386.362.1056</cntfax>
</cntinfo>
</distrib>
<stdorder>
<digform>
<digtinfo>
<transize>3.537</transize>
</digtinfo>
</digform>
</stdorder>
<availabl>
<timeinfo>
<sngdate>
<caldate>unknown</caldate>
<time>unknown</time>
</sngdate>
</timeinfo>
</availabl>
</distinfo>
<metainfo>
<metd>20040421</metd>
<metc>
<cntinfo>
<cntorgp>
<cntorg>Avineon Inc.</cntorg>
<cntper>Keith Patterson</cntper>
</cntorgp>
<cntpos>Director of Photogrammetry, mapping and GIS</cntpos>
<cntaddr>
<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
<address>15500 Lightwave Drive, Suite 200</address>
<city>Clearwater</city>
<state>Florida</state>
<postal>33760</postal>
<country>USA</country>
</cntaddr>
<cntvoice>727 - 539-1661</cntvoice>
<cntemail>kpatterson@avineon.com</cntemail>
</cntinfo>
</metc>
<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
<mettc>local time</mettc>
<metextns>
<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
</metextns>
</metainfo>
</metadata>
