<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20190225</pubdate>
                <title>Suwanee River Water Management District (SRWMD) 2016-2017 Land Use</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <onlink>http://publicfiles.dep.state.fl.us/OTIS/GIS/data/SRWMD_LANDUSE_2016_2017.zip</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>This dataset, created by the Florida Department of Environmental Protection's Watershed Services Program within the Division of Environmental Assessment and Restoration, is an inventory of Land use - Land Cover classified in the State of Florida's Suwannee River Water Management District and based on 2016 or 2017 True color photography. Classifications are provided for level 1, 2, 3 and a few level 4 (indicated in Land Use and Land Cover Code fields) land uses.See Metadata for contact information.</abstract>
            <purpose>Analyses of Land Use - Land Cover GIS information provide environmental scientists an understanding of the relationships between human activities, land surface physiography and water resources. Florida's landscape is quickly changing and as a result, at the time prior to this layer's creation, existing land use - land cover GIS layers for the Suwannee River area were out-of-date. A more current layer was needed to improve the accuracy of these analyses.</purpose>
            <supplinf>Classifications for the following Counties were based on imagery "flown" on the listed dates: (Alachua 20170108-20170209), (Baker 20170116-20170210), (Bradford 20160119-20160124), (Columbia 20151203-20160120), (Dixie 20160119-20160210), (Gilchrist 20160119-20160210), (Hamilton 20151227-20160130), (Jefferson 20151113-20151123), (Lafayette 20151207-20151219), (Levy 20160119-20160210), (Madison 20151227-20160130), (Suwannee 20151203-20160120), (Taylor 20151207-20151219), (Union 20160119-20160124)</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <rngdates>
                    <begdate>20151113</begdate>
                    <enddate>20170210</enddate>
                </rngdates>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>flight dates</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>None planned</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-84.009165</westbc>
                <eastbc>-82.029991</eastbc>
                <northbc>30.66013</northbc>
                <southbc>29.085361</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>environment</themekey>
                <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>LULC</themekey>
                <themekey>Land Use</themekey>
                <themekey>Land Use Land Cover</themekey>
                <themekey>Planning and Development</themekey>
                <themekey>Land Cover</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>None</placekt>
                <placekey>Suwannee River Water Management District</placekey>
                <placekey>Florida</placekey>
                <placekey>SRWMD</placekey>
                <placekey>Suwannee River</placekey>
            </place>
            <temporal>
                <tempkt>None</tempkt>
                <tempkey>2016</tempkey>
                <tempkey>2017</tempkey>
            </temporal>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>This data is intended to be used for general informational and planning purposes, and is not appropriate for legal and/or cadastral purposes.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Division of Environmental Assessment and Restoration, Watershed Services Program</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Andrew Morris</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>Environmental Consultant</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>2600 Blair Stone Road</address>
                    <city>Tallahassee</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>32399</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>850-245-8426</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>Andrew.Morris@dep.state.fl.us</cntemail>
                <hours>8:30-4:30, M-F</hours>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>Florida Department of Environmental Protection's Division of Environmental Assessment and Restoration, Watershed Services Program</datacred>
        <native>Version 6.2 (Build 9200) ; Esri ArcGIS 10.6.1.9270</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <logic>No statistical accuracy verifications have been done.</logic>
        <complete>There are no significant omissions</complete>
        <lineage>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>By exporting all features of the SRWMD 2013-2014 Land Use Land Cover layer to a feature class in a standalone file geodatabase from the Florida Department of Environmental Protections Spatial Data Engine, it was then modified for editing purposes. Modification to the feature class was limited to adding or removing fields and setting domains for pre-existing or new fields. Dataset revision started and completed using the 2016 and 2017 aerial imagery provided by the Florida Department of Revenue. A request from the SRWMD to code all center pivot irrigation fields as ‘2104: Row Crop’ was adhered to. At the completion of the revision, modifications to the feature class then consisted of deleting fields and creating new fields. New fields were populated with separate portions of the attributed Land Use or Land Cover fields (note: these had both the code and description in one field prior to separation) into multiple fields. Two fields, Level 1 Description and Level 2 Description, had attribute data populated based on a table join from a standalone spreadsheet. Check Geometry tool was run, no violations found. Topology was run and 4 errors (Rule: Must Not Have Gaps) existed but all are exceptions (3 as islands, 1 as the circumference of the dataset). Review of a concatenated field (Land Use Code + Land Cover Code) was used to identify, after running ‘Summarize’ on that field, if any Land Use and Land Cover combinations were used that might deviate from the standards set in the Photo Interpreter Key for dual coding. This process is run a couple times a month per the QA workflow and any anomalies noted and discussed then.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20190215</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Obtained data for a new layer from DEAR and added the same in the GIS library.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20190225</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntorgp>
                            <cntorg>Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP) OTIS/GIS Section</cntorg>
                        </cntorgp>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                            <address>2600 Blair Stone Rd MS 6520</address>
                            <city>Tallahassee</city>
                            <state>FL</state>
                            <postal>32399-2400</postal>
                            <country>US</country>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntemail>GIS.Librarian@dep.state.fl.us</cntemail>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>254206</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>BASE.SRWMD_LANDUSE_2016_2017</enttypl>
                <enttypd>Florida Department of Environmental Protection, Land Use Land Cover data for the Suwannee River Water Management District (2016-2017)</enttypd>
                <enttypds>Florida Department of Environmental Protection</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_1_CODE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The first highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land use, Cover and Forms Classification System</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1000, 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, 6000, 7000, 8000</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>FLUCC's system is hierarchical; it includes four levels that build in terms of specificity: A Level 1 classification is the most general, it is a four digit code in which the first integer in the code is assigned one of eight numbers; 1000 = Urban and Built up class, 2000 = Agricultural, 3000 = Rangeland, 4000 = Upland Forests, 5000 = Water, 6000 = Wetlands, 7000 = Barren Land and 8000 = Transportation, Communications, Utilities.</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_1_DESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A brief textual definition describing a type of land use based on the highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land use, Cover and Forms Classification System</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Textual definition describing a type of land cover.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_2_CODE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The second highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1100,1200,1300,1400,1500,1600,1700,1800,1900,2100,2200,2300,2400,2500,2600,3100,3200,3300,4100,4200,4300,4400,5100,5200,5300,5400,5500,5600,6100,6200,6300,6400,6500,7100,7200,7300,7400,7500,8100,8200,8300</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>FLUCC's system is hierarchical; it includes four levels that build in terms of specificity: A Level 3 classification is the second most general, it is a four digit code in which the first integer in the code is assigned one of eight numbers (referencing a Level 1 classification) and the second integer in the code is assigned a value of 1-9 (referencing the Level 2 classification).</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_2_DESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A brief textual definition describing a type of land use based on the second highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land use, Cover and Forms Classification System</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Textual definition describing a type of land cover.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_3_CODE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>The third highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1-7, 9 (##value0)</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>FLUCC's system is hierarchical; it includes four levels that build in terms of specificity: A Level 3 classification is the second most specific (Level 4 being the most), it is a four digit code in which the first integer in the code is assigned one of eight numbers (referencing a Level 1 classification) and the second integer in the code is assigned a value of 1-9 (referencing the Level 2 classification). The Level 3 integer being 1-7 or 9. Each corresponding integer referencing a Level 3 classification more specific then the Level 2 classification.</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LEVEL_3_DESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A brief textual definition describing a type of land use based on the third highest level designation in a hierarchical coding scheme containing 4 levels.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Textual definition describing a type of land cover.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LANDUSE_CODE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Number given to a specific type of land use</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1110-8390</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Number given to a specific type of land use</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LANDUSE_DESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A brief textual definition describing a type of land use</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Textual definition describing a type of land cover.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LANDCOVER_CODE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Number given to a specific type of land cover</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <edom>
                        						
                        <edomv>1210-8390</edomv>
                        						
                        <edomvd>Number given to a specific type of land cover</edomvd>
                        						
                        <edomvds>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</edomvds>
                        					
                    </edom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>LANDCOVER_DESCRIPTION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>A brief textual definition describing a type of land cover</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Florida Land Use, Cover and Forms Classification System or NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Textual definition describing a type of land cover.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                    					
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                    				
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.AREA</attrlabl>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
        <overview>
            <eaover>The adopted classification scheme is a result of the following process: 1. Classification types were originally taken from the Florida Department of Transportation’s “Florida Land use, Cover and Forms Classification System” (FLUCCS 1999). 2. Conformity with SJRWMD's classification system was sought where ever possible out of an interest in creating a data layer that was seamless in terms of its geometry and attribution with this contingent area. Over the production cycle (this being the 5th iteration) of this data slight changes to the seamless geometry link have been broken. 3. Division of Environmental Assessment and Restoration (DEAR) staff reviewed a preliminary list to identify classification types that contributed to sources of pollution or identify natural conditions that may have an effect on water quality impairment. This led to the removal of some classification types from the preliminary list. One codes has been added in this (5th) iteration of revision, ‘8315: Electric Power Sub Stations’.4. Photo interpreter and managers of the program reviewed the available photography to determine which categories of the DEAR list could and could not be classified. For example, the resolution of the imagery allowed a photo-interpreter to confidently assign the level 3 class code of 2140: Row Crops to a polygon but not of any of the Level 4 codes (see next item). 5. The FLUCC's system is hierarchical; it includes four levels that build in terms of specificity: A Level 1 classification is the most general, it is a four digit code in which the first integer in the code is assigned one of eight numbers; 1000 = Urban and Built Up, 2000 = Agricultural, 3000 = Rangeland, 4000 = Upland Forests, 5000 = Water, 6000 = Wetlands, 7000 = Barren Land and 8000 = Transportation, Communications, Utilities. The second integer (and each successive integer) provides a sub-classification of a higher specificity. For example, 2100 (Level II) Class is ‘Cropland and Pastureland’ a subtype of the 2000 Agricultural class, 2150 (Level III): Field Crops is a specific subtype of the 2100 Cropland and Pastureland subtype. Further, 2153 (Level IV) is a specific subtype of the 2150 class. Level 4 classification is minimal with less than 5% of the database using Level 4. This is due to the lack of image resolution in the source imagery that is needed to pick out key identifiers as well as the time of year the imagery was captured. The Level 4 designation is indicated in either the Land Use Code or Land Cover Code Fields of the attribute table. 6. A few classification types were added to accommodate needs that were specific to the Water Management districts.</eaover>
            <eadetcit>NWFWMD/SRWMD Land Use Land Cover Photo-Interpreter Key</eadetcit>
        </overview>
    </eainfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20190225</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Florida Department of Environmental Protection (FDEP) OTIS/GIS Section</cntorg>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>2600 Blair Stone Rd</address>
                    <address>MS 6520</address>
                    <city>Tallahassee</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>32399-2400</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntemail>GIS.Librarian@dep.state.fl.us</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
